[footsteps]
INOMATA
[Yukiko] Hey! You are on a roll, Chinatsu!
We're so proud!
I am so, so happy for you!
Count on me to cheer you on.
We've got to have you strong
for nationals.
- We'll have a feast tonight.
- [Chinatsu] Thank you so much.
[emotional music playing]
[Taiki] That's great.
Chinatsu made it through to nationals.
That's great.
Amazing.
That's amazing!
She said she would,
and she did it. That's...
really cool.
Even though...
[referee] In!
Game.
Twenty-one eleven, twenty-one thirteen.
Yusa of Sajikawa High School wins.
Even though...
[runs, pants]
even though...
I lost.
[opening theme song playing]
BLUE BOX
EPISODE 9
I'LL BE ROOTING FOR YOU
[insects trilling]
[kids laughing, running]
[kid 1] Hurry up!
[kid 2] Wait!
[kid 1] Slow poke!
OYASU SHRINE
[school bell chimes]
[Taiki] I have nothing left.
I'm at my limit.
There's nothing left to do but give up.
Finals are gonna kill me!
FINALS IN 7 DAYS
Why do exams have to be
right after the tournament?
That's why I said
study little by little, dude.
Time for practice.
Studying a little here and there
is the hardest thing
to do in the whole world.
You say it like it's so easy to do.
[exclaims] You'll never understand me!
You're really in your feels.
[playing instruments]
Hey there, girl!
Hey, how's it going?
Which category are you going for?
I'm thinking recitation.
MATHEMATICS
[Taiki] We still have practice
during finals week.
When I get home,
I don't have any energy left for studying.
- You don't struggle finding time to train.
- [exclaims]
Hina!
Could you do me a favor
and not talk to me?
If it ain't Spanish, then I do not
have room in my brain for it right now.
At long last, a friend who understands me.
[Hina] Oh, no, we are not
in the same category.
I've never gotten an F before!
I haven't gotten one either!
- [Hina] Second year of junior high.
- Dude, I had a stomachache!
[Hina] Oh, uh-huh, whatever you say.
[girl 1] Keep it up!
- [girl 2] Come on!
- [girl 3] Here!
[girl 2] Yeah!
Girls' basketball
is already back to practicing.
- Focus on your legwork!
- Yes!
Focus!
- Defense! Defense!
- Come on. Let's go!
- Yes!
- You got this!
There's only two months until nationals.
They do extended practices at night, too.
Yes!
MATHEMATICS
Well, we can't let them show us up!
Okay, let's forget about studying
and practice, practice, practice!
Taiki's on the struggle bus, huh?
[Kyo sighs]
[Hina] After he lost at qualifiers,
he said something like, he expected it
to turn out that way, but still...
And then of course
Chinatsu got into nationals, so...
home life must be weird.
Based on what I've heard,
they haven't really talked much lately.
With practice and exams going on.
Gotcha.
[Kyo] She's not the type
to hear that and feel happy about it.
Taiki will be just fine, I'm sure.
Immediately getting over stuff that's hard
for him is Taiki's strong suit.
[Hina] When you're right, you're right!
[Coach Yuasa] Well, then! Once again,
Kengo Haryu,
congrats on qualifying for nationals!
It's a damn good thing, too.
If Sajikawa nabbed all the spots,
that would grind my gears.
[Haryu] That's all?
I couldn't have done it without you all.
And until nationals,
I might be a bit of a thorn in your side,
but your support means everything.
[chuckles] Bring it on, my man!
I don't need your help.
What!
I said I'd help!
You won't be playing doubles for a while.
Guess you're right.
Okay. Having said all that,
now that things have calmed down,
I want each of you to write down
your goals and put 'em on the wall.
Our goals, huh?
What should we write down?
I wanna shoot for something ambitious.
WITH FORTITUDE AND RESOLUTION
- KASAHARA
[Okayama] Uh, what does that mean?
Strong and decisive.
- All righty. I'm all done.
- Hm?
- [giggles]
- Hold on a sec, Nishida.
MAKE NATIONALS!
- NISHIDA
If you made a mistake,
you should've started over.
I put my feelings into it,
so the message carries!
- [scoffs]
- [Nishida] Hm?
What's yours, Haryu?
WIN NATIONALS (THIS YEAR IF POSSIBLE)
- HARYU
[Nishida] Could you not put that
right above mine, man?
Yeah, we should put
Haryu's goal on the ceiling!
What? Maybe putting it
on the ceiling would "seal" the deal!
- Yeah.
- [both laugh]
Done.
[Tanikawa] Taiki, pass me the tape?
Sure!
INCREASE MY SMASH PRECISION
- INOMATA
[Coach Yuasa] And you. Write on there that
you won't get any failing grades, huh?
[Nishida] Coach, I'm not gonna write
something down that I can't actually do.
- [chuckles]
- [Coach Yuasa] I swear, Nishida...
[Taiki] Here.
[Tanikawa] Thank you!
[speaking accented Spanish]
[player 1] You got it!
[player 2] Let's go!
- [player 3] Vamos!
- [player 4] This isn't Spanish class, man!
[uplifting music playing]
[Chinatsu pants]
- Keep it up!
- Yes! Yeah!
[sneezes]
Do I have a cold?
Guess I should take a break.
[Yukiko] Oh, Chinatsu, welcome back.
They keep you out late these days!
I know, I'm really sorry about that.
Oh, no! No sweat at all, it's fine!
Don't worry yourself on our account.
It's for nationals, after all.
[Chinatsu] Thank you for understanding.
TAIKI
CHINATSU
[silence]
[insects trilling]
- [Nishida] Finals week is over!
- [all cheering]
- Yes, yes!
- This about killed us all!
- We made it through!
- Hm. Hm.
Even after finals,
we didn't skip practice!
No matter what,
we made it through,
and that's what counts!
[both] You heard him! That's right!
Let's celebrate at a restaurant.
Yeah, dude!
- Nishida's paying, everybody!
- [exclaims]
I'm there, man!
[Nishida] Wait! Who decided that?
Do you think you're gonna join them?
[groans, trembles]
I'm gonna pass on this one.
Whoa, are you okay, dude?
I just got a bit short on sleep.
If I go rest at home, I'll be fine.
I gotta come back
full-force to practice starting tomorrow!
See you guys later!
- See you, Taiki.
- See you later.
[door closes]
- It's about time we all headed out.
- Let's eat.
INOMATA
[footsteps]
[groans]
My head hurts.
I definitely have a fever.
I want some Pocari.
But no one's here to help me.
And I cannot, under any circumstances,
get Chinatsu sick.
Oh, this is bad.
[groans]
It's times like these...
[emotional music playing]
I remember the bad things.
I was just starting to forget
about all that, thanks to exams.
If I weren't sick,
I could go run and clear my head.
[coughs]
[breathing heavily]
You have to go to nationals.
Thank you.
Taiki Inomata.
Don't be too careful with it.
I'll win the next one.
That's the spirit.
But...
I think he's gonna be a real force.
Gotcha.
Don't drive yourself crazy overthinking.
You just gotta show 'em
what you're made of.
Please... please... I pray for both
Chinatsu and I to make it to nationals.
Then score... one more!
[grunts]
[exclaims]
I'm a total loser.
[Chinatsu] That's not true.
[footsteps approaching]
[Taiki gasps]
You're burning up.
[gasps]
[Chinatsu] Is everything all right?
[thuds]
Hang on? Chinatsu?
No, please, don't. You can't be in here.
I'm not feeling good.
- It'd suck if you got it, so please--
- Can you stop already.
If you're sick, then you should be quiet.
Okay.
[quirky music playing]
COOLING PATCH
- [knock on door]
- Uh. Come in.
I thought that you should eat something,
and I found some udon noodles.
Udon...
Did Chinatsu make me food?
- All right.
- [door closes]
[Chinatsu] It sounds like
Yukiko is going to be back late.
Sorry that the food is so simple.
Thank you so much.
She made me a home-cooked meal.
Thanks for the food.
[blowing]
My nose is so stuffed,
I can't even tell what it tastes like.
Just tell me
if there's anything else you need.
I appreciate it.
Hm?
Nothing.
It's been a while
since we've been this close.
Two capsules is the dosage, right?
[Taiki] Um...
I'm okay now, really.
You can head back to your room, Chinatsu.
I'll stay here till you fall asleep.
You never know,
you might start feeling a bit worse.
I'm not feeling tired at all, though.
Then, can we just talk for a little while?
'Cause it's been chaotic
with all the tournaments and finals,
we haven't really talked.
And besides,
you mentioned a question the other day.
You said there was something
you wanted to ask me
once the tournament was over?
Um, Chinatsu.
After tomorrow,
could I ask you one question?
Oh, did I say something like that?
Don't play dumb with me, Taiki.
[chuckles] Oh, no, I'm not playing dumb.
[sniffles]
It's just that...
I had the confidence then, to ask her.
[Chinatsu] Seeing Hina...
it made me jealous.
Okay, then can I ask you a question?
Yeah.
[Chinatsu] I saw that the badminton team
put up their goal sheets today.
[Taiki gasps]
And knowing you,
I thought that your goal
would be going to nationals.
[gentle music playing]
So I want to know
why is it that you wrote
something different?
It's because...
I've gone over it so many times
in my head about that smash...
What if it had been in?
I've also felt like the nationals
might've been setting my sights too high.
Once I made it to the tournament,
there were so many people
way better than me.
You know what it's like.
How tough it is
to make nationals as a first year.
And in spite of that,
you still had determination.
I just wanted it. I...
wanted to go and win.
So I thought maybe I was out of my depth.
[chuckles]
Wait, what?
Are you laughing at me?
I'm sorry.
So even the great Taiki
sometimes doubts himself.
Oh, thank you for the food.
I hope you liked it.
I mean, I figured
you might think those things...
but I thought you were the type
who'd never let on about it.
Well, it's actually...
This is your chance.
Why not reinvent yourself?
[exclaims softly]
You can still set an ambitious goal,
and keep checking in with yourself.
[Taiki] But right now,
that ambitious goal is...
[Chinatsu] You said
that I am always determined...
but in the back of my mind,
I'm also wondering...
"Am I aiming too high?
Is this impossible?"
Sometimes, all I would feel is pressure...
[laughs]
and I'd ask myself,
"Why don't I just ease up?"
But then I would
hate myself for thinking that.
That said,
what got me out of bed early
every morning...
was wanting to go to nationals.
If there's something that you wanna do,
or something you wanna be,
I want you to feel good about that.
I don't want you to be afraid
to set your sights on something big.
No matter how big it might be.
If that goal motivates you to keep going,
then I believe that's good enough.
And it's those people
I wanna root for.
[gasps]
[coughs]
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Sorry. You should get some rest.
[Taiki sighs] I...
really like this side of her.
She's had these feelings and doubts...
but has worked through
all of them on her own.
So she's an empathetic,
and kind soul.
I'm going to add onto my goal sheet.
All right.
Well then, I'll get this out of the way.
No, I can do it.
It's fine! You just sleep.
[Taiki] But...
[thudding]
[Taiki] I'm sorry.
[gasps]
I got up and lost my balance.
Huh?
[closing theme song playing]